Is it the state of Lebanon that is shelling
это государство Ливан обстреливает
Israel or is it some people whom
Израиль или это какие-то люди которым
the state of Lebanon allows to fire at
государство Ливан разрешает обстреливать
Israel. Well, of course it’s some people, it’s
Израиль Ну это конечно какие-то люди это
Hezbollah, well, how, how, in principle, people
хизбалла ну как как как в принципе люди
in Lebanon are not against it, of course there are a
в Ливане не против конечно есть очень
lot who are against it, but the majority are
много которые против но большинства
for it.
за
Hello Hello, where are you from?  where are you
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы откуда вы
from? I’m from Finland Helsinki Yeah, you
откуда Я из Финляндии Хельсинки Ага
speak Russian, yes Well, I’m originally from
по-русски говорите да Ну я родом из
Rostov, now in Finland Helsinki, I
Ростова сейчас в Финляндии Хельсинки 18
’ve been living for 18 years, in 2 years it will be the
лет живу через 2 года будет
twentieth And in Russia now, how
двадцатого А в России сейчас да как
long ago it’s been 2 years, and Russian where they taught Russian in
давно 2 года а русский где учили в рус в
Russia and such good Russian
России и такой хороший русский
already yes Well, I'm at the
уже да Ну я в
university And you're from Lebanon, you're
университете А вы из Ливана вы
a Christian, a Muslim,
христианин мусульманин
I'm an atheist, I understand Well, who's nationality? I
я атеист понял Ну а по национальности
mean, well, ethnic, who's
кто В смысле Ну этнический кто араб там
Arab, what group is Arab? Yes, Arab, because in
какая группа Араб Да араб потому что в
Lebanon There are different ethnic groups,
Ливане Там есть разные группы этнические
I know different religious ones. Well, no, they're all Arabs,
знаю разные религиозные Ну нет все Араби
but  different religions let's say
но разные религии скажем
Arabs Christians yes it turns out there is
так арабы христиане да получается есть
no Well, even Christians they are Arabs
нет Ну даже христиане они арабы
and how is the infusion now this is
а как сейчас вливание вот
why the war is why the war I'm
чего война а из-за чего война Вот мне
interested because Israel
интересно потому что Израиль
is Yeah and what is Hezbollah you have
это Ага а что такое хизбалла у вас
Hezbollah is  What is a political party like? A
хизбалла - это Политическая партия как
political party if it is an
это Политическая партия если это
armed formation not with
вооруженное формирование у не
troops. Well, political. Well, not only
войска Ну политическая Ну не только
political. Well, look. There is
политическая Ну что вот смотри Есть
a state of Lebanon, yes, yes, the state of
государство Ливан да да э у государства
Lebanon has an Armed
Ливан есть Вооружённые
Forces, of course. And then what is Hezbollah
силы конечно А тогда что такое хезболла
with some, what kind of group is it?
с какими-то что это за группировка с
armed
вооружёнными
forces Well, this is a difficult
силами Ну это сложный
question that in history yes yes because in
вопрос что в истори да да потому что в
history lefno it has always been like this uh because of the
истории лефно всегда так было э из-за
history of Lifan that is Everyone has
истории лифана то есть У каждого есть
their own weapon let’s say
своё оружие скажем
every person in every group even
каждого человека у каждой группы даже
Christians Christians have owls like but
христиане у христиан сов есть типа но
that’s before  was No, look, what is
это раньше было Не ну смотрите В чём
the essence of the state Yes, the state has
суть государство Да у государства есть
an army, other armies in the state no yes yes yes yes
армия других армий в государстве нет да
yes Well, Well, of course this is a very
да да да да Ну вот Ну конечно это очень
difficult question, but why does Hezbollah have
сложный вопрос но зачем вот у хизбалла
weapons That’s the question yes
оружие есть Вот в чём вопрос вот да
why Lebanon Why Lebanon doesn’t  will destroy
почему Ливан Почему Ливан не не разрушит
this group of some kind of Hezbollah
эту группировку какую-то хизбалла у себя
on its territory, no because you know
на территории нет потому что знаете
the state is not
государство не
against Hezbollah having weapons, it’s not
против чтобы у хизбалла были оружие не
against it and like the People, well, of course there are a
против и как Народ ну конечно есть очень
lot of us who, look, I
много ны которые так вот смотрите я я
just read, I’m not good at history there and
просто читал я не силён в истории там и
yours  Yes, but I read that Hezbollah was
вашего Да но я читал что хизбалла там
shelling Israel there, it was like that
обстреливала Израиль было такое
No, well, you need to look at history, don’t go
Нет ну надо смотреть историю не поди
stop stop stop Well, yes,
поди по стоп стоп стоп Ну да Ну хизбалла
look, Hezbollah is not the state of Lebanon Yes, but some
смотри не государство Ливан Да а
Hezbollah from the territory of Lebanon
какая-то хизбалла с территории Ливана
is shelling Israel, it was
обстреливает Израиль было
like that, it was like that, it was like that  It
такое было Да было было то вот интересно
turns out interesting.
получается
Well, is it the state of Lebanon that is shelling
Ээ это государство Ливан обстреливает
Israel, or is it some people whom
Израиль или это какие-то люди которым
the state of Lebanon allows to shell
государство Ливан разрешает обстреливать
Israel? Well, of course, these are some people, this is
Израиль Ну это конечно какие-то Люд это
Hezbollah, well, how, how, in principle, people
хизбалла ну как как как в принципе люди
in Lebanon are not against it, of course there are a
в Ливане не против конечно есть очень
lot who are against it, but the majority are for A
много которые против но большинства за А
wait, who Look, here is Hezbollah Who
подожди а кто Смотри вот э хизбалла Кто
elects it here is the state Yes the
её избирает вот государство Да
state Yes there are elections Yes
государство Да там есть есть выборы Да
people elect and Hezbollah - it
люди избирают а хизбалла - это
turns out some people gathered for themselves,
получается какие-то люди себе собрались
took weapons and fired at Israel
взяли оружие и обстреляли Израиль так
or not no no no in their parliament I do
или нет нет нет нет в парламенте у них
n’t know  how many deputies is this? But this is the
не знаю сколько это депутатов Но это
largest by No, well, this is a party in
самый большой по по Не ну это партия в
parliament Yes, but who is who? Yes, they were
парламенте Да а кто кто им Да
allowed to authorize shelling at another state That’s the question Yes,
им разрешили Вот в чём вопрос Да
no one no one
никто никто
Hmm, the question is of course difficult. And if you
Хм вопрос конечно сложное А если вы вы
look, who will allow them, why do they
смотрите вот кто им разрешит зачем они
without without the consent of the state, this is of course the
без без согласия государства это конечно
right question, let’s say this, but it’s a difficult
вопрос верный скажем так но это сложно
question. Well, I’m just very glad that
вопро Ну вот я как раз очень хорошо что
you came across to me. I’ve always wanted to
вы попались мне вот Я всегда хотел
understand these events in the Middle
разобраться в этих событиях на Ближнем
East, yes. For me, this is interesting
Востоке да Для меня это интересно вот
for for us and for Lebanon.  Arabs
для на для нас и для Ливан Для арабов
for Muslims especially not only for
для мусульманин особенно не только для
Muslims Well, in principle, for Arabs this is
мусульмани Ну в принципе Для арабов это
first and foremost and then for Muslims
в первую очередь и потом для мусульман
Israel is an enemy Why is the enemy not an enemy
Израиль - это враг Почему враг не враг
Look at me now Yes, I don’t
Смотри я сейчас Да я сейчас не
understand now the enemy is not an enemy This is history but
разбираюсь враг не враг Это история да
in my opinion Why do we have a state
во мнете Поче в шем государст есть
some states that are not controlled
какие-то ди которые не контролируются
by the state but can fire at
государством но могут обстреливать
other
другие
states. Well, in order to
государства Ну это
explain it, you just need to
чтобы как объяснить вам просто надо
explain the history because it was
объяснить историю потому что это было
100 years ago, so 100 years ago, not 100 years
100 назад так 100 лет назад не 100 лет
ago, yes, I was before
назад смот Да я пом е е когда-то был
when I was  Prophet
когда был е Пророк
Koche people walked around in skins Yes, we are pressing
коче люди в шкурах ходили Да вот мы жим
now Yes, no, we are pressing now, but this is the Armed Forces,
сейчас Да нет мы жим сейчас но это ВС
this was all after the war after the
это всё было после войне после
civil war in Lebanon, that is, after the
гражданской войны в Ливане то есть после
nineties, it doesn’t matter after not after
девяностых годов неважно после не после
now look now there is a state of Lebanon
сейчас смотри сейчас государство Ливан
Now why does Hezbollah have its own weapons
есть Сейчас зачем у хизбалла своё оружие
Yes, no, why does Khila have weapons? I know
есть Да не зачем у хилы оружие Я знаю
Hezbollah wants to fight, Hezbollah,
хизбалла хочет воевать это хизбалла вот
this is a terrorist
это террористическая получается
organization, if it is a
организация если она если
state, why
государство Зачем
terrorists? I’m not saying that
терористи Я не говорю что
they look, look, I don’t know at all,
этон они смотри смотрите я вообще не зау
I understand, yes, I’m interested in what I’m not for.
я понимаю да мне интересно что я не за
But why terrorist?  question
Вот Но зачем террористический во вопрос
If this is not terrorism the law is legal Yes the
Если это не терористи закон законны Да
law is like a law you have a law about the
закон как закон у у вас есть закон про
Khiz Bal that they are allowed to have weapons
хиз балу что им разрешено иметь оружие
Yes this is what we call in Lebanon How how how is it
Да это это у нас в Ливане называется Как
translated in Russian Well
как как переводится на русском Ну
when we have a new How government they
когда у нас новое Как правительство они
write let’s say  a
как пишут скажем
document of their goals about their how, you know,
документ их цели о их как ну знаете вот
and in each of these it is written that this
и в каждом из этих написано что этот
Hezbollah and other organizations that are
хизбалла и другие организации которые
fighting against Israel are legal, that’s
воет против Израиля они законны вот
cool. And where can I where what do you call
прикольно А где можно где как называе
now I read the post interesting now now
сейчас прочитал посл интересно сечас
now I don’t know it’s being translated now
сечас сечас Я не знаю переводится сейчас
it turns out look  if this is if then
то получается смотрите если это если то
Hezbollah if it is legal then it is
хизбалла если это законная значит это
part of the state system No not
часть государственной системы Нет не
often So wait
част Так подождите е
a second okay who is subordinate to come
секундочку хорошо кому подчиняется давай
on So who is the armed
давай Так кому подчиняется вооружённая
group subordinate to Hezbollah
группировка хизбалла
What to whom Well to whom to the head of Lebanon UN to
Что кому Ну кому кому главе Ливана ООН
whom
кому
Who rules the hello who is in charge
Кто управляет хило кто главный
listened to So  look he doesn't give a [ __ ]
на слушал ко Так вот смотри насрала он
who is the
кто
online head
онлаин глава
If you have an army on you
Если у вас есть армия на вы имеете в
mean Iran Yes no no over the army over the
виду Иран Да нет нет над армией над
army Do you have a boss the president
армией У вас есть начальник президент
for example yes or there is the head of the government
например да или там глава правительства
Yes and who is the boss over
Да а кто начальник над
[ __ ] no one but that is it turns out and the
насрало никто а то есть получается а
state does not obey  I
государство не подчиняется эта структура
don’t understand this structure And another interesting question: What
нет понял А ещё интересный вопрос Какое
relationship does Hezbollah have with the IRGC Yes, with the
отношение хизбалла имеет с ксир Да с
Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps in
корпусом страже исламской Революции
Lebanon Oh, not Lebanon But Ira
Ливана Ой не Ливана А Ира
Well, of course they have a very good relationship,
Ну конечно у них очень хорошее отношение
it’s all because of the religious reason,
это всё из-за религиозной причины
see the IRGC Yes, the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps
смотрите ксир Да корпус страже исламской
in Lebanon it  also oh in Iran
революции в Ливане он также ой в Иране
it is also not that it is not subordinate to the
он также не это не подчиняется
state like Khibla yes Yes, that’s right Well,
государству как хибла да Да всё верно Ну
this question is very complex How so is
вот это вопрос очень сложны Как так так
Khila controlled by the
управляется управляется ли хила корпусом
Islamic
стражей исламской
Revolutionary Guard Corps No seriously, I didn’t say that,
Революции Нет серьёзно я то не сказал
let’s do that Iranian
давай так иранские
Generals are sitting in Lebanon and instructing
Генералы сидят в Ливане и инструктирует
Hizb  Yes, no, they don’t control, but they
хизб Да нет не управляют а помогают
help, they help, Yes, that’s what I’m saying,
помогают помогают Да это вот я я говорю
they are one and the same, that is, Hezbollah and
они они одно и то же то есть хизбалла и
Iran are
Иран это
like one thing, not Iran, not Hezbollah and
как одна вещь пони не Иран не хизбалла и
Iran. But Hezbollah and the
Иран А хизбалла и корпус стражей
Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps in Iran even said
исламской революции в Иране сказал даже
Iran Iran Not  look at Iran, there is the
Иран Иран Не смотрите Иран вот Есть
state of Iran And there is a guard corps,
государство Иран А есть корпус стража
these are different things, these are different things, but as in
это разные вещи это разные вещи но как в
Iran. We know very well that this is the same thing,
Иране Мы хорошо знаем что это одно и
not in Iran, in Iran, just like
тоже нет в Иране в Иране так же как и
Hezbollah, you get Iran declares
хизбалла у вас получается Иран заявляет
that it will not, but the guard corps  takes and
что он не будет а корпус стражи берёт и
fires at
обстреливает
Israel, this turns out to be parallel
Израиль это получается параллельные
structures, that is, in the state. Yes, there is
структуры то есть в государстве Да есть
some kind of
какая-то те
group. Why is it terrorist,
группировка Почему террористический она
it is not subordinate to the state?
не она не подчиняется государству это
guards of the Islamic Revolution to
Иране корпус стражи исламской Революции
whom does he
кому он
obey he does not obey the President of
подчиняется он не подчиняется президенту
Iran correctly he is this what is it Le
Ирана правильно он этот как его это Ле
yes and this Le obeys yes
да а это Ле подчиняется да
it is like in the system of Iran Who Who is
это Это как в системе Ирана Кто Кто
the head of Iran like who is the most important in Iran
глава Ирана как кто самый важный в Иран
or look there is a president who is
или смотри есть президент который
elected by the people and there is like  spiritual
избирают люди а есть типа духовный Лидер
Leader here is a spiritual leader He is more important than who
вот духовный лидер Он важнее чем кто
elects a spiritual
избирает духовного
leader no one And who
лидера никто А кто его
appointed him no one And where does he come from
назначил никто А откуда берётся он
why does he obey the spiritual
почему ему подчиняется духовному
I don’t, well, this is in the Iranian system of
ли я не ну это это в системе Иране
understanding this is in the system of Islam there is no in the
понима это это в системе Ислама нет в
system of Islam Islam for example there
системе Ислама Ислам например
is no Khalifa there  stop stop this is not a caliphate,
там Халифа нет стоп стоп это не халифат
just look at how the caliphate is they they shi
как раз смотрите как халифат это они ши
but it’s like, in principle, a spiritual leader
но это как в принципе духовный Лидер вот
in religion in Islam the democrats are not at all
в религии в исламе демократы вообще не
Well that’s right Hov Where does who come from For
не Ну правильно Хов Откуда берётся кто
example in this the Pope Yes he is
Вот например в этом Папа Римский Да его
elected by the Kato cardinals Yes these are there
избирают Като кардиналы Да вот эти там
other priests Who elects who
другие священники Кто избирает кто
appoints this spiritual leader of Iran
назначает этого духовного лидера Ирана
Well, I don’t know how he just
Ну не знаю как он просто сам типа
says himself, Let me be the spiritual leader Oh
говорит Давайте я буду духовный Лидер О
this is an assistant this is ha how is his huma Yes
это помощник это ха как его хума Да
who died the previous one yes Well who is him
который умер предыдущего да Ну а кто его
who accepted him as the spiritual
кто его принял духовным
leader
лидером
Well you are today  spiritual leader
Ну сва вы сегодня духовным лидером
obey me to fire at Israel I don’t
подчиняйся с мне обстрелять Израиль Я не
know the answer I don’t know the answer Tell me if you
знаю ответ я ответ не знаю Скажите если
know I’m interested, that is, it
знаете вот мне интересно то есть
turns out uh And why then in
получается ээ А зачем тогда в
the state of Iran there are elections for the President of
государстве Иран есть выборы президента
Iran, this is a formality, a formality I
Ирана это формальность формальность
understand, interesting, that is, the president is
понял интересно то есть президент - это
just a Talking doll for the UN  Yes And
просто Говорящая кукла для ООН Да А
yes, I wouldn’t say that, well, I don’t know, I’m
так да я бы это не сказал ну не знаю я
not Iranian at all. I don’t know about Iran and
вообще не иранец Я не знаю про Иран и
about their system, it’s just that I, I, when I
про их систему вот просто я я я когда
started, I’ve literally been studying
начал я буквально ээ полгода там изучаю
these events there in the Middle East for six months.
вот эти события там на Ближнем Востоке
I’m very interested, yes I  I thought that it was
Мне очень интересно да я думал что это
Israel fighting there with Lebanon Israel with
воюет там Израиль с ливаном Израиль с
Iran it turns out that in Lebanon there is
Ираном оказывается что в Ливане есть
some kind of Hezbollah that simply does not
какая-то хизбалла которая просто не
obey the state Yes, in Iran there is
подчиняется государству Да в Иране
some kind of Islamic Revolutionary Guard corps
какой-то корпус стражи исламской
that does not obey
Революции который не подчиняется
the state Yes, it stands above the state,
государству Да он стоит над государством
some kind of armed formations
какие-то вооружённые формирования
are obtained  interesting yes Well this is of course
получаются интересно да Ну это конечно
interesting but the question is a complex question
интересно но вопрос сложный вопрос
complex you need to understand the history well
сложный надо понять историю хорошо
question When and when Hezbollah fires at
вопрос Когда когда хизбалла обстреливает
Israel and Israel Well for example
Израиль так и Израиль Ну вот например
Hezbollah shot at Israel Yes Israel
хезболла обстреляла Израиль Да Израиль
can fire back of
может делать ответные обстрелы
course but who
конечно но кто
started Look who started who started when it
начал Смотрите кто начал кто начал когда
started this is a war  So I’m saying you need to
начал это вот война Вот я говорю надо
understand history. If you look, well,
понять историю Если вы смотрите Ну как
who started the war, it’s a war that didn’t start stop
кто начал война это война не начала стоп
stop stop Let’s go on like this now The war
стоп стоп Давай так сейчас идёт Война
between Lebanon and Israel yes Lebanon is at war
между ливаном и израилем да Ливан воюет
or the war between the former and Israel
или война между хиз былой и израилем
Lebanon exactly
Ливан точно
when when this war began between
когда когда началась эта война между
Lebanon and  Israel Well, how much today is
ливаном и израилем Ну сколько сегодня
this, well, a month ago a month And this is when
это ну месяц назад месяц А это когда
Israel entered this into the territory of
Израиль зашёл на это на территорию
Hezbollah yes And before I was waiting for Hezbollah
хизбалла да А раньше была жду хизбалла
and the question is a question yes I would even say this is
и вопрос вопрос да Я бы даже сказал это
Israel’s war against Lebanon I would even
война Израиля против Ливана Я бы даже
stop stop stop against Lebanon or against
стоп стоп стоп против Ливана или против
Hezbollah  against Lebanon all against all
былы против Ливана всего против всего
Lebanon So stop, you know well how many just
Ливана Так стоп хорошо знаете сколько
just you know So let's
просто просто знаете Так давайте так
you know how many peaceful people are
знаете знаете сколько мирных людей
now now now now and how many are Hibla
сейчас сейчас сечас смо а сколько хибла
That's why Israel entered the territory
Вот почему Израиль зашёл на территорию
where Hezbollah is based
где хизбалла базируется
Why
Зачем
by Why Because Hezbollah fought with
по Почему Потому что хизбалла воевали с
Israel so stop  then now the war
израилем так то стоп то сейчас война
started with Israel or Hezbollah fought with
началась израилем или хизбалла воевала с
Israel that again then look it
израилем что ещё раз то смотрите
turns out it’s a month you say a month is going on
получается месяц вы говорите месяц идёт
War don’t hang up don’t hang up don’t hang up
Война не Зависай не Зависай не Зависай
ay-ay-yay such interest about
ай-ай-яй такой интерес о
the weight you can hear me yes yes it’s stuck Yes
развес слышно меня да да вот зависло Да
so uh Now I’ll look and  op fired at
так э Сейчас я посмотрю а оп стреляла
Israel I just saw yes last year
Израиль Я просто видел да в прошлом году
this year it was that Hezbollah
в этом году было что хизбалла
fired at Israel so now
обстреливала Израиль так сейчас
let's see But who started the war who
посмотрим вот Но кто начал войну кто
come on so when When you said that the
давай так когда Когда вы сказали что
war started a month
война началась месяц
ago No well it's It's like today's
назад Нет ну это Это как сегодняшняя
war you know but war is like war  between
война понимаете но война как война между
Israel
израилем
[music]
[музыка]
and 2 months ago there was a war between
и 2 месяца назад была война между
Israel and Lebanon, did it
израилем и ливаном была то она месяц
start a month ago or was it 2 months according to
началась назад или она была 2 месяца по
the law according to the law according to the law Yes, the war
закону по закону по закону Да война
began in forty-eighth
началась сорок восьмого
year forty-eighth year between
года сорок восьмого года года между
Lebanon and
ливаном и
Israel and then there were measures  once again
израилем а потом была меры ещ раз
let's take it like this Let's
давайте так ээ возьмём Давайте прошлый
take last year Let's take last year you have a war going on
год возьмём прошлый год у вас идёт Война
Last year there was a war with
в прошлом году была война с
Israel the twenty-third year 2023
израилем двадцать третий год 2023 год
was in what month 2023 was the year according to the
был в каком месяце 2023 год зако по
law there was a
закону была
war, look it was uh
война вот смотрите была это ээ
Like how
Как как
we have it  this war between Lebanon and
её вот у нас эта война между ливаном и
Israel between Israel even and and the
израилем между израилем даже и и и
Arab world Yes no No let's
арабским миром Да на не Нет давайте
now we are not the Arab world There is no such
сейчас мы не Арабский мир Нет такого
thing The Arab world good
понятия Арабский мир хорошо хорошо
good good Jordan Arab and Jordan Arabs
хорошо Иордания араб а Иордания арабы
they don't fight for example with Israel
они не воюют например с израилем
true ho good I agree between
правда хо хорошо я согласен между
Lebanon  and Israel is the War at the beginning of the
ливаном и израилем это Война начало
forty year, then after I don’t know
сорок вого года потом через не знаю
some time it was good
некоторых время было пере хорошо
Truce, you had
Перемирие вот у вас в прошлом году было
a Truce last year Yes Internationally, super yes
Перемирие Да По международному супер да
I Why did you want to You wanted to ask
я Почему вы хотели Вы хотели спросить а
why the war then Yes, no, I look, look
почему война потом Да не я смотрю смотри
if there was a Truce  Yes, I see I
если было Перемирие Да вот я смотрю Я
discovered on Wikipedia the shelling of Israel from
открыл в Википедии обстрелы Израиля с
the territory of Lebanon Yes, 2023 is just a
территории Ливана Да вот 2023 год просто
bunch in short Yes, for example So on April 6,
короче куча Да вот например Так 6 апреля
23, in the afternoon 34 missiles were fired at Israel from the south of Lebanon
23 днём с юга Ливана по Израилю выпущено
if this is a Truce Yes this is
34 ракеты если это Перемирие Да вот это
this when oh twenty-third year
это это когда ой двадцать третий год
last  year April 6 July 6 two anti-
прошлый год 6 апреля 6 июля две противо
missiles were fired from you know you know that
ракеты были выпущены с знаете знаете что
we have Lebanese territory which
у нас ливанская территория которая
Israel captured it again again
Израиль захватил её ещё раз ещё раз
look so you have a truce now or
смотрите так у вас сейчас Перемирие или
not now not 2 months ago it was
нет сейчас нет 2 месяца назад было в
last year there was a
прошлом году было
truce until October 8 until 8  October So
Перемирие до 8 октября до 8 октября Вот
I’m counting until October 8 if you had a
я считаю до 8 октября если у вас было
Truce Yes, from the territory of Israel
Перемирие Да вот из территория Израиля
on July 6 they fired at the city of Gaja Yes
вот 6 июля обстреляли по городу гаджа Да
from the south of Lebanon Here is Gajar this is this
с юга Ливана Вот гажар это это это
Lebanese once again once again you have a
ливанский ещё раз ещё раз у вас
Truce like this on October 8 like this Well,
Перемирие так во так 8 октября так Ну а
then  already Okay October so for the first year
дальше уже Окей Октябрь так д первы год
Yes for the first year I’m also looking at three
Да д первый год вот смотрю тоже три
missiles from the Layli area towards
ракеты из района лайли в сторону
Northern Israel were fired like this on
Северного Израиля были выпущены так 14
May 14th And so
мая И так
on Well, what is the question then if
дальше Ну то есть какой вопрос то если у
you had a Truce why did you fire at
вас было Перемирие зачем вы обстреливали
Israel you know about
Израиль знаете об
[music  ]
[музыка]
this is 1701 you know about this something that 17 1701
это 1701 знаете об этом что-что 17 1701
I don’t know this is a UN decision of the UN So
Я не знаю это ООН решение ООН Так что
after after after the war of the sixth year and
после после после войны шестого года и
what the decision after that was this
что что решение после этого был это
UN decision Yes, that you can’t
решение ООН Да что нельзя
how Israel can’t attack Lebanon and
как Израилю нельзя нападать по ливану и
and also And Lebanon  yes according to Israel Yes yes yes
и тоже И ливану да по Израилю Да да да
but
но
with this since when in the sixth year yes before the 1st there
с с это с когда шестого года да до оя
were about 40,000
было где-то 40.000
violations on the part of
нарушений со стороны
Israel let's look like this
Израиля давайте так
Okay 4000 specifically Israel
смотри Окей 4000 конкретно Израиль
fired missiles at your territory Yes Just look at it
обстреливал ракетами вашу территорию Да
now
Во сечас посмот
let's see the shelling
давай так обстрелы
killed
убили
not the leader Yes the leader  I
они не лидера Да лидера я
understand the command, look, can you
понимаю команла смотри можете мне
tell me where I can find it because, for
скинуть где можно найти потому что я
example, on Wikipedia I found
например в Википедии я нашёл
shelling of Israel from Lebanese territory.
обстрелы Израиля с территории Ливана
Tell me where can I look at this
Скажите где я могу посмотреть вот эти
list of 4,000 violations, where are these
список 4.000 нарушений где вот эти
shellings? It’s not interesting, but October 8. But it’s
обстрелы не интересно а 8 октября А вот
just interesting. You said October 8
просто интересно Вы сказали 8 октября
this was last year on October 7th, it was Hamas that
это ж в прошлом году 7 октября это Хамас
attacked civilians Yes in Israel Why
напал на мирных жите Да в Израиле Почему
civilians on civilians I saw Well
на мирных жителей на мирных Я видел Ну
it was also at a festival there was a
тоже это на фестиваль там же был
festival And they saw what he
фестиваль А видели что
wrote Once again
написал Ещё раз ещ раз
stop stop stop the whole world saw it like
стоп стоп стоп это видел весь мир как
Hamas  militants transported a woman from Germany
Хамас боевики женщину возили из Германии
with broken legs, this is 100% true Well,
с поломанными ногами это 100% правда Ну
look at what you saw, what the Israeli wrote
сколько с смотрите Видели что написал
this,
это
what that most of the
израильский что что большинства мирных
Israeli civilians who were killed on
жителей Израиля которые были убиты 7
October 7 who Who killed them who was not Hamas not
октября кто Кто их убил кто не Хамас не
Hamas from Sahal from Sahal this this this this
Хамас от сахал от сахал это это это это
this  this is this I’m not this I’m not saying this is an
это это это это я не это я не говорю это
Israeli newspaper I understood I understood that is, it was the
газета Израиля понял понял то есть это
Jews themselves who killed their people on purpose
специально евреи сами убили своих людей
Yes this is the same thing the Russians
Да это вот нам так же само россияне
tell us about the riot that it was we ourselves who
говорят про бучу что это мы сами
killed our people no This is
поубивали своих людей нет Вот это потому
because Hamas is like the
что Хамас как
seventh crib  Yes, they entered
седьмого криб Да вошли в
the territory of Palestine, this is the territory of
территорию палестине это территория
Palestine, they entered Yes And so they captured
Палестины они вошли Да И вот захватили
some piles, let's say Hamas Hamas, there
некоторых кипу давай так Хамас Хамас там
were peace Hamas raster, don't hang out damn
были мир Хамас растре не Зависай блин
such an interesting
такой интересный
person, develop it again Hamas shot
человек ещё раз разви Хамас расстреливал
civilians at a
мирных жителей на
festival at a festival no f no a lot of people were
фестивале на фестивале нет ф нет куча
apparently killed at this  festival, it spread all over the
видно убитых на этом фестивале это весь
world. Now I’ll send you
мир облетело Вот я сейчас вам отправлю
this
этот
report, newspaper, look again, that
э-э репортаж газета смотри ещё раз то
is, watch the video of how
есть смотри ээ видео как э
Hamas is with the Hamas video. Yes, there
хамасом есть с видео Хамаса Да видео
is a video of how Hamas transported this
есть как хамасом возили эту гражданку
German citizen with broken legs,
Германии с поломанными ногами
torn clothes, and so on. Yes, they
разорванной одеждой и так дальше Да
transported  They were killed in a car, it’s true It’s
возили На машине убиты это правда Это
true It’s true It’s all true, but it
правда Это правда Это всё верно а
turns out the question is the question is not
оказывается вопрос вопрос вопрос не
why but why why why do you
почему а зачем зачем зачем вы мне
tell me, well, I don’t know You are for
скажите ну я не знаю Вы же это вы за
Hamas Tell me why are they a
Хамас Скажите зачем они гражданку
German citizen That’s it, I’m not for Hamas, wait
Германии Вот так я не за Хамас подождите
I’m not  for
я не за
Hamas for the truth Let's So you condemn
Хамас за правду Давайте Так вы осуждаете
these terrorist actions of Hamas
эти террористические действия Хамаса
then so but you called it
тогда так а вот вы назвали это
terrorist Well yes when they take when
террористический Ну да когда берут когда
they take a peaceful woman they break it stop
берут мирную женщину ломают ено стоп
when Israel kills let us now
когда Израиль убивает давайте мы сечас
residents of e You look you are afraid you are afraid
жителе е Ты смотри ты боишься ты боишься
you are afraid to answer the answer  I asked you first
ты боишься ответить отве Я тебе первый
I asked you first you will answer Look,
задал Я первый задал ты ответишь Смотри
you count when Hamas catches a
ты считаешь когда Хамас ловит гражданку
German citizen Yes, her legs and carries her naked in a
Германии Да ей ноги её и голой возит на
car and
машине и тери
she starts on October 7th, then this is absolutely
те начало 7 октября то это абсолютно
terrorism but there is but of course but the war did not
терроризм но есть но конечно но война не
start October 7th began before that
началась 7 октября началось до этого
E  even in the twenty-fifth year or even in the
Э даже двадцать пятого года или даже
seventeenth year 2 on the seventeenth, I
семнадцатого года 2 п семнадцатого я
understand correctly that since the war
правильно понимаю что можно раз война
began in the seventeenth year, you can
началась семнадцатого года можно граждан
catch citizens of some country. And what about
какой-то страны ловить А вы что от
Hamas and the Palestinian people, tell
Хамаса и от палестинского народа скажите
me if if you are watching If
мне если если вы вот смотрите Если
now I don’t know Ukraine or
сейчас не знаю Украина или
let's say so if the United States captured yes the
скажем давайте так если США захватила да
Russian Federation well not No, let's
Российской Федерации хорошо не Нет
look now Russia
давайте вот смотрите сейчас Россия
has captured Ukraine Yes, part of the territory Yes,
захватила Украину Да часть территории Да
look Ukrainian Ukrainian
украински смотри украинские
Soldiers Ukrainian soldiers Ukrainian
Солдаты украинские солда украинские
soldiers Ukrainian Soldiers Yes, they are liberating the
солда украинские Солдаты Да освобождают
territory I have not seen such a thing as
территорию Я не видел такое чтобы
Ukrainian Soldiers catching some
украинские Солдаты ловили какую-то
woman
женщину убива
while killing  In short, you didn’t see it in Kursk, you didn’t
во Короче не видели в Курске вы не
see it in Kursk in the Kursk region, you saw
видели в Курске в Курской области видели
the course that what Ukrainian Soldiers killed
курс что что украинские Солдаты убили
like Ukrainians show me show me
как украинские покажи покажи мне покажи
come on now on the phone Open for me
давай вот сейчас на телефоне Открой мне
give ours - who are you Lebanese no
давай наших - это кого ты ливанец нет
it’s Russian so Are you Russian or Lebanese I’m
это русских так Ты русский или ливанец я
Russian  So you’ve been living in Russia for 2 years
русский Так ты же 2 года живёшь в России
and have Russian protection. And how are you Russian by blood? are
да покрови русской А как ты по крови
you in the shower in the shower in the shower or in the
ты в душе в душе в душе или в
bath? Well, come on, show me on video Yes on the
ванне А ну давай покажи мне на видео Да
phone where the Ukrainian soldiers
на телефоне где там украинские Солдаты
were bullied, driven around
издевались возили
Come on, what do you have to do with you, you bear
Давай причём ты ты несёшь
responsibility here  these civilians
ответственно вот этих мирных жителем
Because you support Why don’t I
Потому что ты поддерживаешь Почему я не
Support wait wait you
Поддержи подождите подождите ты
justify
оправдываешь
the women You say Well, no no no
женщи говоришь Ну как проти Нет нет нет
I don’t have anyone Nobody doesn’t care Okay,
я никого нет никого не по Хорошо давай
so you condemn
так ты осуждаешь
that German citizen as Hamas No,
хамасом той гражданки Германии Нет
of course
конечно
No, that means you support
Нет значит поддерживаешь
I no, I don’t support anyone, come on  so once
Я нет я не поддерживаю никого давай так
again you condemn or support
ещё раз ты осуждаешь или поддерживаешь
Hamas for that
хамасом вот той
woman. I am against this, that means you
женщины Я против этого значит ты
condemn Hamas and oh everything. Otherwise you are
осуждаешь Хамас да о всё А то ты
not saying
говоришь не
this. Come on,
Вот это Давай
now Israel has killed how many
тепер Израиль убили сколько мирных
civilians in the Gaza Strip Yes, that means
жителей в секторе Газа Да значит
Look, I don’t know how many, but I think I
Смотри я не знаю сколько но я думаю я
count  that
считаю что
teno I you let's do so Hamas
тено я те давай так Хамас
terrorist organization is 4 5000
террористическая организация это 4 5000
people 5.000 correct Yes look I'll
человек 5.000 правильно Да смотри я вот
say this yes means yes Hamas Hamas
что скажу да значит да Хамас Хамас
terrorist organization Yes this is not
террористическая организация Да это не
fat Here is fatf look fatf Yes this is an
фат Вот фатф смотри фатф Да это
organization for the liberation of Palestine Dafa the
организация освобождение Палестины Дафа
legitimate power in Palestine
законная власть в палестине
terrorist more boor  and Hamas and
террористическая больше хама а Хамас а
Hamas yes Oh even in Palestine because the
Хамас да О даже в палестине потому что
Gaza Strip if it is uh
Сектор газа если он ээ
supported Palestine Palestinian
поддерживается Палестина палестинские
authorities Yes who is Hamas Hamas is a
власти Да кто такой Хамас Хамас - это
group that in Palestine
группировка которая в палестине
Palestine is responsible when the code state
палестине отве когда кода государство
any state when any
любое государство когда любое
state
государство
kills bodies this state the
убивает ных телей это государство
state Israel is at war with  the
государство Израиль воюет с
terrorist group Hamas,
террористической группировкой Хамас
which occupies a huge territory in the
которая занимает огромную территорию в
gas sector, 45,000 civilians,
секторе газа 45.000 мирных жителей смоли
tar, tar, what Oh, he is he, in short, he also
смоли что О он он это он короче уже тоже
says that nothing happens in Ukraine,
говорит что в Украине ничего не бывает
so look Why why Yes why the
так вот смотри Почему почему Да почему
Arab state of Egypt did not
государство Египет аское арабское не
allow civilians to enter Egyptian territory
дало мирным жителям выйти на территорию
Why What again Why Egypt Yes didn’t
Почему Что ещё раз Почему Египет Да не
give to civilians And why should they,
дал мирным жителям А почему они должны
well, wait, look now it’s
были ну подожди вот вот смотри сейчас
coming, look it’s going on War Yes, the
идёт идёт смотри идёт Война Да
terrorist organization Hamas and the
террористической организации Хамас и
state of Israel are the official
государство Израиль официального
state and the terrorist
государства и террористической
organization Yes, not the state of Palestine
организации Да не государство Палестина
Yes, because in
Да потому что в
Romelen is at war with  Israel Yes, Romola is not
ромален воюет с израилем Да ромола не
fighting, some Hamas is fighting, it’s just in
воюет воюет какой-то Хамас это просто по
your opinion the question why Egypt Yes didn’t not
вашему мнению вопрос почему Египет Да не
let in a refugee and they say we won’t
не пустил к себе беженца а сказа мы не
let them in, why and why not Well, well, well,
пустим их почему а почему нет Ну это ну
these are the Arabs of the Arabs, you are our question, this is this,
это ж арабы арабов вы это наш вопрос это
this is the question  You said in short the
это это вопрос Ты ты говорил короче
Arab world you said the Arab world
Арабский мир ты говорил Арабский мир
against Israel Yes, let's do it Egypt
против Израиля Да давай так Египет
the question the question is the question is Why
вопрос вопрос в том вопрос в том Почему
should they run away That's because because because
они должны убежать Вот потому что потому
yes When there are
что потому что да Когда идут боевые
hostilities Yes when here, for example,
действия Да когда вот у нас например
there are hostilities Yes Ukraine
идут боевые действия Да Украина
is evacuating its citizens Yes, it is evacuating from the
эвакуирует своих граждан Да эвакуирует с
border territory Yes, Russia is
приграничной территории Да вот Россия
evacuating from its territory there. Why
эвакуирует там со свои территории Почему
Yes, why is Hamas not evacuating, but
Да почему Хамас не эвакуирует а а
hiding behind civilians because
прикрывается мирными жителями потому что
Hamas are terrorists, they are holding
Хамас террористы они держат в заложниках
these people hostage, so it turns out that who said
этих людей так получается это кто сказал
I said I said How do you know?  I
Я сказал я сказал А вы откуда знает я я
know I studied This question I pretended to
знаю Я изучал Это вопрос я притворялся
you for half an hour Why don’t I know that’s
тебе полчаса Да что я не знаю это
all I’ll tell you I’m in Helsinki Yes I
всё я я скажу я в Хельсинки Да я
teach oriental studies Yes 18 years of
преподаю востоковедение Да 18 лет
practice in 2 years I will have my
практики через 2 года у меня будет
twentieth I’m a university professor so
двадцатое я профессор университета так
that’s when you told me about  hilu
вот и когда ты мне рассказывал про хилу
about xir And so on Yes, I
про ксир И так дальше Да я Красиво
smiled beautifully Yes, because I knew that you were
улыбался Да потому что я знал что ты
blatantly deceiving You say you
нагло нагло обманываешь Ты говори ты
support Yes, you support
поддерживаешь Да ты поддерживаешь людей
peaceful people, yes Because when Hamas
мирных да Потому что когда Хамас
attacks and peaceful people you start, it’s
нападает и мирных людей ты начинаешь это
not Hamas, it’s Sahal, yes, you said that I  I was
не Хамас это сахал да ты это сказал я
specially waiting to unpack you
специально ждал чтобы тебя распаковать
Yes, you support the terrorist
Да ты поддерживаешь терористи
organization Russian Federation Because
организацию Российская Федерация Потому
when it captured the territory of
что когда она захватила территорию
Ukraine you say that yes, this is
Украины ты говоришь что да это
the territory of Russia, this is what you
территория России это ты
say, this is what you say Yes, and
говоришь вот это ты говоришь Да так и
now yes, the state of Israel Yes, it is
вот сейчас да государство Израиль Да
fighting with the terrorist organization
воюет с террористической организации
Hamas, which is not under  control in
Хамас которая не под контрольна
Palestine Yes, in Palestine in Ramal
палестине Да вот в палестине в ра мале
So tell me This is who there is no you
Вот скажи ко Это это кого нет нет вы
say I’m for Israel and for Palestine and
скажите я за Израиль и за палестину и
against Hamas
против Хамаса
about
про
wait I asked I asked a very very
подожди я задавал я задавал очень очень
very simple question let’s not
очень простой вопрос давай дох пор не
do it until then I answered I support Look I
хотите я ответил Я поддерживаю Смотри я
I support Israel’s war against the
поддерживаю войну Израиля против
Hamas group Yes, in which
группировки Хамас Да в которой гибнут
Hamas hostages are dying, all of whom are now
заложники Хамаса которые сейчас все
45,000 Yes, because yes Because Hamas
45000 Да потому что да Потому что Хамас
Yes, huge Koli How many militants in the Hamas group are
Да огромная Коли Сколько в группировке
super I don’t know how many Hamas militants
боевиков супер Я не знаю ско боевиков
I’m not in
Хамас я не в
Hamas I’m not in Hamas And how many, well, well  what are
Хамас я не в Хамас А сколько ну ну что
you doing right away? 10 where 20.000 20.000
ты сразу давай так 10 где 20.000 20.000
o 20.000 Koman super grouping where they are
о 20.000 группировка коман супер где они
all where they are all
все где они все
located this to me here they are located
расположены это мне вот они расположены
in this small patch
на этом маленьком пятачке который
called the Gaza Strip what is the question question
называется Сектор Газа что вопрос вопрос
uh who is the leader of Palestine you are a
э кто руководитель Палестины вы
professor yes Correct yes who is the
профессор да Правильно да кто
leader of Palestine Name  I want to know who is the
руководитель палестин Назови мне кто
head of the Palestinian Authority,
руководитель палестинской автономии
why autonomy and not a state
а почему автономия а не государство
because you haven’t made a state, the
потому что государство вы не сделали
Palestinians haven’t made a state yet,
палестинцы ещё не сделали государство
they are moving towards creating a state Well,
они идут к созданию государства Ну
because they proclaimed a state,
потому что провозгласили государство
there is because because the head of the
есть потому потому что глава
Palestinian Authority is the head of
палестинской автономии есть главы
state, there is no head of state yet And how many
государства нету пока А сколько
Israelis again  look there is a
израильско ещё ещё раз смотри есть
Palestinian AB Who is the head of the Palestinian
палестинской АВ Кто глава палестинской
Autonomy Mahmoud Abbas Yes he announced he is
автономий Махмуд Аббас Да он объявлял он
now at war with Israel he no no so that is,
воюет сейчас с израилем он нет нет так
that is, we see that Palestine is
то То есть мы смотрим Что Палестина с
not fighting with Israel right and no
израилем не воюет правильно а нет
wrong Wrong Of course it is
неправильно Неправильно Конечно
wrong if half the people Vova
неправильно если половина народа Вова
again Who represents Palestine
ещё раз Кто представляет палестину
Look  who represents Palestine Who
Смотри кто представляет палестину Кто
who represents the Russian Federation you
кто представляет Российской Федерации вы
me Putin Putin Yes head Who represents
ме Путин Путин Да глава Кто представляет
Ukraine Zelensky head Who represents
Украину Зеленский глава Кто представляет
Israel Prime Minister Israel Who
Израиль премьер-министр Израиль Кто
represents Palestine you said Mahmoud
представляет палестину ты сказал Махмуд
Abas correctly
Абас правильно
No not only he not only he so stop
Нет не только он не только он так стоп
Who who then not only this is Palestinian
Кто кто тогда не только это палестинская
liberation organization once again once
либератион ная организация ещё раз ещё
again Who represents Palestine the
раз Кто представляет палестину
entire Palestinian people Who represents I
палестинский народ весь Кто представляет
will not answer anymore until they answered
отвечать больше не буду пока не отвечали
my simple question How many times have I
на мой простой вопрос Какой ещё раз я
already answered this is it terrorism or not I
ответил уже это это терроризм или не я
answer you this is not terrorism the action of
тебе отве это не терроризм действие
Israel is not terrorism I answered everything
Израиля не терроризм Всё я ответил
now look at my Answer my question
теперь смотри на мой На мой вопрос
Yes, who does leadership mean if
отвечай Да кто значит руководство если
you say that it is not Mahmoud Abbas who
ты говоришь что не Махмуд Аббас
leads Palestine
руководит палестиной
who did you say that this October Yes no
кто вы сказали что сеь октября Да нет
again once again Make sure we understand
ещё раз ещё раз Смотри чтобы мы поняли
Hamas - are they terrorists or not terrorists
Хамас - это террористы или не террористы
because you are very cunning  it turns out that
потому что у вас очень хитро получается
yes, in Lebanon there is Lebanon And there is Hezbollah,
да в Ливане есть Ливан А есть э хизбалла
which does not obey the state and
который не подчиняется государству и
attacks Israel in Palestine, there is Hamas,
атакует Израиль в палестине есть Хамас
which By the way, yes, it is fighting against
который Кстати да он воюет и против
Palestine Hamas is against Ramal, the truth is
Палестины Хамас против рамал правда
against,
против
but I won’t answer, so look Hamas
а я отвечать не буду пому смотри Хамас
again, say Hamas against
ещё раз скажи Хамас против
Ramal, I’ll answer  I won’t until you
рамал я отвечать не буду пока вы не
answered I answered your
отвечали Я же тебе ответил на твой
question I will support Israel’s actions This is
вопрос Я поддержу действия Израиля Это
not Terrorism this is not terrorism Yes I
не Терроризм это не терроризм Да я тебе
answered you Look I answered this is terrorism
ответил Смотри я ответил это терроризм
when Hamas killed 100 or 150 residents of
когда Хамас убил 100 или 150 жителей
Israel I absolutely look if if
Израиля я абсолютно смотри если бы
look if Hamas attacked  on the army on the
смотри если бы Хамас напал на армию на
IDF, yes that would be different,
цахал да это было бы другое
if you look where they attack
вот если смотри они куда нападают ещё
again, look again if Hamas attacked the IDF,
раз смотри если бы Хамас напал на цахал
yes As a result, more civilians died,
да В результате чего погибли ещё мирные
this could be understood Yes,
жители это можно было бы понять Да
because then you would say you
потому что тогда бы вы сказали вы
fought against Halo in
воевали против Хало
the army attacked  on
вцерм нападал на
this one like a dance that song in reality
э этот как танцева та песн в реальности
Hamas attacked I you saw how They
Хамас напал Я те Вы видели как Они
destroyed the Israeli tanks
уничтожили израильски танки Я тебе
I now I'll show you now I'll show you now
сейчас я тебе сейчас покажу я тебе
look I'll show you now I just didn't
смотри я тебе сейчас покажу прям не
see I look I'll show you now I saw I'll
видел я смотри я сейчас покажу Я видел я
show you now  what happened with this with the Rei
сейчас тебе покажу что было с этим с Рей
festival I saw it and you saw 45,000
фестивалем я это видел а вы видели 45000
civilians once in this at this at
мирных жителей раз в этом на этом на
this Rei festival there were uh were now now
этом Рей фестивале были э были сейчас
now there were
сечас сейчас были
military No this is this in general This is general I do
военные Нет это это вообще Это вообще Я
n’t know what to say at all here the militants are
не знаю что сказать вообще вот боевики
boorish more than 260  man to Israel Israel
хама больше 260 человек Израилю Израиля
can yes 45.000
может да 45.000
As video
Ась видео
how we are now where are we going Hey hello hello
как сейчас мы куда Эй алло алло
Has damn where did he
Хас блин куда
run off come on for them give for us and the hall
убежал давай за них давай за нас и залу
for Hamas And how they fried this one it was
за Хамас А как прожарили этого это было
awesome just
Офигенно просто
usually we fried and here I am
обычно мы прожариваем а тут этого я Нет
No I’m not Yes you  you condemn
я нет Да ты по осуждаешь
Yes, why? Because Hamas Yes, not Israel
Да почему Потому что Хамас Да не Израиль
just took and started bombing something
просто взял и начал что-то там бомбить
Yes, but Hamas, the terrorist organization
Да а Хамас террористическая организация
Hamas attacked Israeli civilians
Хамас напала на мирных жителей Израиля
Yes, it’s just that everyone saw this game, everyone
Да просто это эту дичь видели все все
saw the whole world, yes, people at the
видели весь мир видел да людей на
festival, and a huge number of damn
фестивале да огромное количество блин
260  yes, these are only those that were
260 да э это только те которые были
confirmed, yes, in other cities there
подтверждены да вот в других городах вот
was a bunch of all this. It was visible, yes.
куча было всего такого Это было видно да
And now it turns out that Israel, yes, is
А теперь получается когда Израиль Да ээ
conducting an operation against these
проводит операцию против этих
terrorists.
террористов Да которые та вот он 20.000
snout Yes, of course, if
сидят на этом пятачке Да конечно если
they are hiding in these buildings like yes,
они прячутся в этих зданиях типа да идёт
it’s not like that Yes, they say there
Это не то что Да вот они говорят там
Russia Russia attacked Ukraine, it’s not
Россия Россия напала на Украину это не
Ukraine that came to Russia and began to
Украина пришла э в Россию начала
cut out some settlements there Yes, and
вырезать какие-то там поселения Да и
Russia is conducting a special operation in response, no,
Россия проводит в ответ спецоперацию нет
that’s not at all  another because Israel is
это совсем другое потому что Израиль
defending itself Because there is a
защищает себя Потому что там
terrorist group there and he
террористическая группировка и он он это
understands it because Hamas And who
понимает потому что Хамас А кто Вот
Look, this is not Palestine, these are some
посмотрите это не Палестина это какие-то
dudes who seized power in the Gaza Strip,
чуваки которые захватили в секторе газа
expelled the Palestinian authorities there from there
ээ власть изгнали туда оттуда власти
and said We are here Let’s keep it
Палестины и сказали Мы тут Будем
short Gangs  groups, yes, that’s how it
короче Банд группировки да такие
turns out, that’s all official
получается вот и всё официальная
police autonomy Yes, in the city of Romola
полицейская автономия Да в городе ромола
and on the so-called West Bank
да на так называемом Западном береге
Yes, it is not at war with
Да она не воюет с
Israel Israel does not do anything there, but the
израилем Израиль не это ничего там не
Palestinians live normally for
делает да живут нормально палестинцы
some reason
почему-то
because Hamas
потому что Хамас
Gaza
Газа
Yes, there are no official authorities  Palestine
Да нету официальных властей Палестины
because Hamas cut them all out, yes
потому что Хамас их выпилил всех да
because Hamas is a wild group
потому что Хамас - это дикая группировка
Yes, a terrorist group
Да террористическая
that essentially leads Iran Yes, just
которая руководи по сути Ираном Да также
like Hezbollah
как хизбалла
is all these proxies, Hezbollah is also
это все эти прокси вот хезболла также он
yes and not No, it’s just some kind of There is a
да а не Нет это это просто какие-то вот
state of Lebanon And there is  hla
Есть государство Ливан А есть хла
who has weapons, missiles, and so on
который имеет оружие ракеты и так дальше
Yes, Israel is yelling,
Да орет Израиль
of course
конечно
Israel will go to the south of Lebanon Because if they
Израиль вол на юг Ливана Потому что если
fire from there, after this,
оттуда обстреливают вот после этого
after the Hamas invasion, they started
после вторжения Хамаса Они же начали
shooting at it in the first days, I remember
обстреливать это в первые дни я же помню
too, yes, they started shooting at this
тоже да они начали обстреливать ещё это
territory of Israel, of course, Israel  will
территорию Израиля конечно Израиль будет
clean up Hizb there. Absolutely right,
зачищать хизб там Абсолютно верно
Israel did not go there
Израиль не пошёл туда
somewhere to attack Leo. Here are the
где-то нападать на Льва Вот
border Hezbollah, that’s all,
приграничные хизбалла вот и всё также у
Iran also has Iran, the President of Iran
Ирана тоже есть Иран президент Ирана
says no no, we won’t do anything there
говорит нет нет мы там ничего не будем
Israel yes And there is some kind of
Израиль да А есть какой-то корпус стражи
Islamic Revolutionary Guard corps that  has missiles,
исламской Революции который имеет ракеты
drones, and fires, and it’s a very cunning
дроны да и обстреливает да очень хитрая
position. So all these
позиция Так что все вот эти любители
Hamas lovers, go understand, you’re all there too.
Хамаса идите поняли Вы все то там тоже У
We have some people who
нас есть некоторые люди которые
for some reason are very many. By the way, who is from the
почему-то очень многие Кстати кто из
post-Soviet
постсоветского
space there now, who considers themselves
пространства сейчас там кто считает себя
these followers of Islam, they start to type
этим последователям Ислама начинают типа
this is for Hamas And so on Yes, where did
вот это за Хамас И так дальше Да откуда
you get this radical from? Yes, for
вы это радикальные по набирались Да
example,
например
Jordan Yes, he manipulates very cunningly
Иордания Да вот он очень хитро
Hamas does not support
манипулировать Хамас не поддерживают
Lebanon does not support Yes Jordan Arabs
Ливан не поддерживают Да Иордания арабы
Arabs allies of
арабы союзники
Israel when Iran fired at Israel
Израиля когда Иран обстреливал Израиль
uh Jordan also shot down these missiles uh
э-э Иордания ещё сбивала эти ракеты ээ
these Iranian ones  Yes, so that they don’t get there
эти иранские Да чтобы они не долетели
because they were flying through the territory of Jordan
потому что они через территорию Иордании
to Israel, shot down that the
пролетали на Израиль сбивала что
Princess of Jordan was still flying in person on a plane,
принцесса Иордании ещё лично на самолёте
bombed like this, so there’s no need to
летало бомбило вот так что не надо вот
pile this up very nicely, yes, and why did
это очень красиво наваливать да А почему
n’t Egypt, uh, not
Египет ээ не там не
allow a
пустил к себе на
refugee into its territory? Yes, so that  so they
территорию беженца Да чтобы вот их
were brought out, he said, no, we don’t need these Khamas owls,
вывели он сказал нене нам этих ха масов
in short, we don’t need all of these Yes, why
сов короче всех этих не нужно Да почему
And he
А он
he We see what he is He has long become,
он Мы видим что такое он Он давно стала
uh, like it,
ээ
impotent nay, a decayed
оно импотент най э разложившийся
structure that lives for its own
структурой которая живёт себе своих
interests Yes, they fed a bunch of these Onov bureaucrats
интереса Да куча этих онов ских чинуш
from the fact that there is all sorts of help for
кормили из того что там всякую помощь на
Palestine and so on, and now
палестину и так далее пиха и сейчас
when all normal people see What
когда все нормальные люди видят Да что
is this Hamas? What are all these heels?
такое этот Хамас Что такое эти все хилы
Yes, this is all, this is all a manifestation of
да вот это всё вот это всё проявление
this and
вот этой да
North Korean Yes, they are all fighting against the
северокорейской Да они все воюют против
normal civilized world.  and that’s
нормального цивилизованного мира вот и
all, that’s why who supports the boor that
всё поэтому кто поддерживает хама тот
last one,
последний
subscribe comment message on my
давайк подписка комент пись на мий
Instagram I don’t know why this is for
Instagram Я не знаю для чего це тоб Для
Why else is there to marvel at the oce y face
чего ще тоб там дивитись на оце й фейс
Ale for you, one two or three clicks
Але для тебе це один два або три клика
Ale you trime me and I will say Wow  in
Але ты тримае мене и я буду казати Вау в
me there are a bunch of fouls and in me there will be a
мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
cool mood, robiti but cool video
класный настрий щоб робити но крут вдео
message on my Instagram ass Andriy
пись на мий Instagram попк Андрий вот
like this, let me check for you
так давай я тебя чекаю